I'm a 20+ frontend veteran specializing in design systems for the past 4+ years. I approach any project with a creative mindset, able to both build rapidly and ensure quality. I'm a lifetime learner, with a voracious appetite for design and technology.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**BILL,** Remote - Staff Design Technologist, Design Systems 2019-2023

- · Established inaugural design systems including Web Components built using Stencil, Storybook setup & config, and component docs.
- · Developed design system's 2.0 Web Components using Lit, TypeScript and vanilla CSS.
- Developed automated design token services using the Token Studio Figma plugin resulting in >50% improved turnaround time for product rebranding.
- · Implemented theming allowing a single code base to support multiple products and bank partners.
- · Developed component search tool using Node.js and frontend UI for monthly design systems metrics.
- · Served as bridge between design and engineering, improving workflows and handoff via component specs.

# **Bottomline Technologies,** Remote - *UI Developer* 2017-2019

- · Contributed to product code base built using Backbone.js.
- · Developed theming tool to automate theming for multiple bank partners.

## Intridea/Mobomo, Remote - *UI Engineer* 2014-2017

- · Client: National University System. Led engineering team that developed the Sanford SEL iOS and Android tablet app (bit.ly/2V6C6o2).
- · Client: Great Minds. Responsive redesign of greatminds.org front-end using Bootstrap and SASS. Developed living style guide (bit.ly/2mc2b2o).
- · Client: Message Systems. Developed living style guide using KSS, Bootstrap and SASS (bit.ly/2mdb6kZ).

# **Punchbowl,** Framingham, MA - Senior Front-end Developer 2013-2014

• Developed responsive layout for Party Planning site (bit.ly/leBZmML).

## **NESN,** Watertown, MA/Remote - Web Developer 2007-2013

- · Developed web sites & hybrid mobile apps using web standards.
- · Managed initial launch of NESN.com in May 2008.

## **Vertical Communications,** Cambridge, MA - *Web Designer* 2004-2007

- · Rapidly prototyped visual comps and implemented in XHTML 1.0 Transitional.
- · Designed artwork for software releases and trade show signage.

### **EDUCATION**

University of Massachusetts, Lowell, MA 2004 - BFA, Graphic Design

Middlesex Community
College, Lowell, MA
2001 - AS, Liberal Studies
2001 - Web Publishing certificate

## **PROFICIENCIES**

## **Web Languages**

HTML; CSS; SASS; LESS; JavaScript

## **Version Control**

Git; Subversion

## **Programming Languages**

Ruby (views); PHP

#### **UI Frameworks**

Lit; jQuery; jQuery Mobile; Bootstrap; Pattern Lab; Ionic; AngularJS

#### **Applications**

Adobe Creative Cloud; VS Code; Terminal

## **Additional Tools**

Figma Tokens (Figma plugin) Style Dictionary (tokens) Storybook (workshop) ZeroHeight (docs) KSS (living style guides) Gemini (VR testing) Cordova (hybrid mobile apps)

### **EXTRACURRICULAR**

Author of Mobile App Manual: The Blueprint, How to Start Creating Mobile Apps Using jQuery Mobile and PhoneGap Build (mobileappmanual.com).

## **LANGUAGES**

Fluent in conversational Brazilian Portuguese.